

# MING SHUN KWEK

mingshun1998@hotmail.com



Singapore, Singapore



Student of Software

www.linkedin.com/in/kwek-ming-shun

# SUMMARY

Computer Engineering Graduate from National University of Singapore and current Singapore Industry Scholar at Micron Technology. Strong communicator with a determined work ethic. Forward-thinking development professional with expertise in Python, Java and other programming languages. Committed to continuous learning and gaining experience across diverse fields to contribute meaningfully to the world of technology.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Strategic Planning Engineer (Data Analytics)

Micron Semiconductor Asia Pte Ltd | 2023 - Present

- Led capacity planning for CMP manufacturing area through coordination with senior management on engineering changes and optimizing capital expenditures (CAPEX), saving \$12.1M in FY24 for tooling modifications.
- Streamlined departmental workflows by developing Python scripts and managing historical data sets using backend SQL database management, enhancing data retrieval and analysis.
- Spearheaded discussions with Micron's Smart Manufacturing Global Team to develop capacity planning software aligned with current industry practices, intended for widespread use by Micron's planning engineers worldwide.

#### Java Software Developer (Intern)

Integro Technologies Pte Ltd | 2021 - 2022

- Collaborated on Collateral and Limits Management Product (CLIMS), resolving frontend UI issues in JSP by applying industry-standard debugging processes, successfully resolving over 30 issues.
- Troubleshooted backend bugs that made used of Java Spring and Hibernate frameworks, helped identified root causes and formulated corrective action recommendations.
- Created, modified, and maintained software documentation and specifications.

#### **Contracts/Projects Assistant**

YL Integrated Pte Ltd | 2018 - 2019

- Analyzed floor plans to calculate the required lighting and fire emergency equipment for tender projects, facilitating accurate purchases while striving for CAPEX savings.
- Managed communication between suppliers and the company, addressing inquiries regarding quotations and purchase orders.
- Mentored a team of 3 employees, overseeing their training and professional development.

#### Sergeant, 1st Battalion Singapore Guards

Singapore Armed Forces (National Service) | 2017 - 2018

- Planned mission objectives and collaborated with full-time servicemen to optimize battle plans and develop efficient routes for mission success
- Facilitated the training of 30+ recruits as an instructor, teaching and mentoring enlistees. Transitioned to a leadership role post-graduation from Basic Training, taking responsibility for recruits during their active service.

## **EDUCATION**

### National University of Singapore

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering 2019 – 2023

#### Nanyang Junior College

Singapore-Cambridge GCE Advanced Level Diploma 2015 – 2016

#### **SKILLS**

- Java/SQL/Python Programming
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Code versioning (Git)
- Exceptional communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Singapore-Industry Scholarship (SgIS) @ Micron
- NUS Software Development Orbital Programme (Apollo) Advanced Certification
- HSK Chinese Proficiency Test (Level 5) Certification